so let's see if we can figure out the
disk access time suppose we have a disk
that has a thousand cylinders and ten
sectors per track
suppose that the head assembly starts
out at cylinder zero at one end of the
disk and the cylinders are of course
numbered zero through nine 99 suppose
that the speed at which the head
assembly can move is ten microseconds
per cylinder so it's moving at linear
speed and the disk rotates 100 times per
second suppose we have a perfect
controller and the boss or very very
fast relative to this and suppose that
there is no previous request so we don't
have to worry about queuing so the
question for you is what is the average
time to read a randomly chosen byte from
this disk where every byte on the disk
has the same chance of being requested